{"tossups": [{"question": "This battle was formally ended when Charles O\u2019Hara surrendered his sword to Benjamin Lincoln after trying to give it to Lincoln\u2019s commander. This battle was preceded by a battle in which a fleet led by Thomas Graves was defeated by the Comte de Grasse, the Battle of the Chesapeake. For ten points, name this battle where Charles Cornwallis\u2019s forces were defeated by George Washington, the last major battle of the American Revolution.", "answer": "Battle (or Siege) of<b> Yorktown</b> (accept German Battle)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "In one of this man\u2019s novels, Frederic Henry fights during the Battle of Caporetto. In another of his novels, Robert Jordan rigs a bridge with dynamite during the Spanish Civil War. This member of the\u201cLost Generation\u201d drew on his experiences as an ambulance driver during World War One for his novel<em> A</em> <em>Farewell to Arms</em>. When not at his home in Key West, this author frequently went on African safaris. For ten points, name this American author of<em> For Whom the Bell Tolls</em> and<em> The Old Man and the Sea</em>.", "answer": "Ernest<b> Hemingway</b>", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Misc Literature"}, {}, {}, {"question": "Johann Peter Salomon gave this man\u2019s 41st and final symphony the nickname<em> Jupiter</em>. This resident of Salzburg wrote a set of variations on a French folk song, later combined with words as \u201cTwinkle, Twinkle, Little Star.\u201d According to legend, this man left his<em> Requiem</em> unfinished because he was poisoned by Antonio Salieri. The composer of<em> A Little Night Music</em> and the opera<em> The Magic Flute</em>, for ten points, name this 18th-century Austrian composer and child prodigy.", "answer": "Wolfgang Amadeus<b> Mozart</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {}, {"question": "This company\u2019s John Dustin Archbold was almost assassinated in 1915 at Cedar Cliffs by members of the IWW. The Florida East Coast Railway was developed by one of this company\u2019s founders, Henry Flagler. Muckraker Ida Tarbell wrote a \u201cHistory of\u201d [this company].\u201d This company was dissolved after it was found to be in violation of the Sherman Antitrust Act in 1911. For ten points, name this petroleum company that was created by John D. Rockefeller.", "answer": "<b> Standard Oil</b> Company", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This organization had intended that \u201clitter\u201d for a spot off the coast of South Africa, but it miscalculated how quickly debris from its more than 8 ton and 82 feet long piece of equipment would burn up upon re-entry. For ten points, name this American organization that put<em> Skylab</em> into orbit and anticipates a 2028 return to earth of the International Space Station.", "answer": "<b> National Aeronautics and Space Administration</b> (accept<b> NASA</b>)", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "The brothers Gyrth and Leofwine may have been killed early in this battle defending a shield wall composed of troops called fyrds. One side in this battle was massacred in the Malfosse after retreating. That side\u2019s housecarls were able to hold Senlac Hill until an arrow to the eye killed their commander, Harold Godwinson. Depicted on the Bayeux Tapestry, for ten points, identify this 1066 battle that allowed William the Conqueror to take control of England.", "answer": "Battle of<b> Hastings</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "During this conflict, James McFarlane was shot and killed at Bower Hill while attempting to surround and burn a key commander\u2019s house. That man, John Neville, was burned in effigy during this event, while Inspector Robert Johnson was tarred and feathered. After Governor Robert Mifflin refused to put down this insurrection, Lighthorse Harry Lee and the Watermelon Army were dispatched by George Washington to quash the rebel army. For ten points, name this rebellion in Western Pennsylvania sparked by an excise tax on the namesake type of alcohol.", "answer": "<b> Whiskey</b> Rebellion (accept<b> Whiskey</b> Insurrection)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "The beliefs of this Christian denomination were outlined in the Thirty Articles. Hugh Latimer and Nicholas Ridley were two martyrs of this denomination who were burned at the stake in the Marian persecution after Catholic rule was restored. The Act of Supremacy empowered one leader of this denomination which draws heavily from the \u201cBook of Common Prayer.\u201d This denomination was created in response to Clement VII\u2019s refusal to annul the marriage of Catherine of Aragon. For ten points, name this denomination formed by Henry VIII.", "answer": "<b> Anglican</b> Church (accept<b> Anglicanism</b> or<b> Church of England</b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "The book<em> Merchants of Labor</em> chronicles the abuses of workers hired from this country. A minimum wage of 30 cents per hour was instituted as part of a program involving workers from this country which sought to increase contract labor when Americans were away fighting during World War Two. The end of that aforementioned Bracero program involving people from this country coincided with the rise of the United Farm Workers. For ten points, name this country, home to such cities as Guadalajara and Tijuana.", "answer": "<b> Mexico</b> (accept<b> United Mexican States</b>, or<b> Estados Unidos Mexicanos</b>, or<b> EUM</b>)", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "5 million residents, 20 miles north of Tijuana.", "answer": "<b> San Diego</b>, California", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "Judge John Sirica ordered James McCord to provide information about this event, which G. Gordon Liddy orchestrated as head of the Plumbers. During this event, Special Prosecutor Archibald Cox was fired in the Saturday Night Massacre, and the anonymous source \u201cDeep Throat\u201d aided journalists Woodward and Bernstein in uncovering this 1970s scandal. For ten points, name this scandal involving the wiretapping of Democrat Party headquarters at a certain Washington hotel that led to the resignation of Richard Nixon.", "answer": "<b> Watergate</b> scandal (accept answers involving the break-in at the<b> Watergate</b> hotel and the subsequent scandal)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>After John Humphrey Noyes kicked this man out of the Oneida community, he went to Hoboken, New Jersey to start an unsuccessful newspaper called</b><em><b> The Daily Theocrat</b></em><b>. This</b> <b>author of the hymn \u201cI am going to the Lordy,\u201d (+)</b> <b>pleaded for an ambassadorship to</b> <b>France, and this man\u2019s most notable action resulted in the passage of the Pendleton Civil Service Act. \u201cI am a (*)</b> stalwart of the stalwarts\u201d was shouted by, for ten points, this man who fired two shots in the Baltimore and Potomac Railway Station to kill James Garfield.", "answer": "Charles J.<b> Guiteau</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "In 2018, this man became the first African-American to</b> <b>win the Academy Award for Best Animated Short Film for</b><em><b> Dear (+)</b></em> <b>Basketball. Despite</b> <b>disagreements with teammate Shaquille O\u2019Neal, this man won three NBA championships in a row from 2000 to 2002 and five in his career and became known as \u201cThe (*)</b> Black Mamba.\u201dFor ten points, name this Los Angeles Laker who was killed in a helicopter crash in January, 2020.", "answer": "Kobe<b> Bryant</b>", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>This man and his brother served during the British invasion under Aulus Plautius where he commanded Legio II Augusta. That brother, Sabinus, was murdered in Rome while this</b> <b>man\u2019s forces approached the city in the Year of the (+)</b> <b>Four Emperors. This man was</b> <b>a patron of the historian Josephus, and he said right before his death in 79 AD that \u201can Emperor ought to die standing upright.\u201d The construction of the (*)</b> Colosseum began during this man\u2019s reign and was finished during the reign of his successor, Titus. For ten points, name this founder of the Flavian dynasty.", "answer": "<b> Vespasian</b>", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "<b>In one poem by this author, \u201cStout and brave\u201d hearts are likened to \u201cmuffled drums\u201dafter the speaker claims that \u201cLife is real! Life is earnest! / And the grave is not the goal.\u201d This poet wrote about the title character\u2019s love for Gabriel Lajeunesse as the British</b> <b>deported the (+)</b> <b>Acadians during the Great Upheaval in a poem that begins \u201cthis is the</b> <b>forest primeval.\u201d Ojibwe legends serve as the basis for a poem by this author that includes the title character\u2019s marriage to (*) </b> Minniehaha. For ten points, name this American poet of \u201cA Psalm of Life,\u201d<em> Evangeline</em>, and<em> The Song of Hiawatha</em>.", "answer": "Henry Wadsworth<b> Longfellow</b>", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Poetry"}, {"question": "<b>In this state, the Continental Army was trapped by the British behind Assinpink Creek but escaped by keeping their campfires lit while outflanking the British. Alexander Hamilton fired on (+) Nassau Hall during a battle in this state at a university that had rejected him. One battle in this state was fought after George Washington\u2019s army (*)</b> crossed the Delaware River on Christmas night. For ten points, name this state where the battles of Monmouth and Princeton were fought during the American Revolution.", "answer": "<b> New Jersey</b> <b>Extra Question</b> Only read if you need a backup or tiebreaker!", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>This man was once forced to hide in the home of a peasant woman in the Somerset Levels and accidentally burnt that woman\u2019s cakes. That exile came after this man\u2019s defeat at Chippenham. This man later won the Battle of Edington, after which his</b> <b>rival (+)</b> <b>Guthrum was forced to convert to Christianity. The law codex known as</b> <b>the Doom Book was compiled in this man\u2019s reign, as was the (*)</b><em> Anglo-Saxon Chronicle</em>. For ten points, Viking power was checked by what king of Wessex called \u201cthe Great\u2019?", "answer": "<b> Alfred</b> the Great", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}